DEAR X
ALL CHARACTERS, PLACES, AND EVENTS
IN THIS WORK ARE FICTITIOUS
CHILD ACTORS WERE FILMED
WITH GUARDIANS PRESENT
Two, three. Clear!
CARDIAC PACEMAKER
- One, two, three. Clear!
- At that fork
where one life stands
between life and death
what kind of prayer
did desperate Ah-jin
offer up?
At death's door
was that one's life
or one's end?
Was that death
God's answer to Ah-jin's prayer
or His punishment?
WITH DEEPEST CONDOLENCES
No!
Grandma!
EPISODE 8: BEFORE JUDGMENT
SAMYUN SEOUL HOSPITAL MEMORIAL HALL
NOTICE REGARDING MEDIA COVERAGE
REST IN PEACE
Get some rest.
You'll collapse at this rate.
I'll take him outside for a moment.
HONG KYUNG-SUK
- You two know each other?
- Yes.
He helped me out a lot.
And I worked part-time
at his café for a year.
BASEBALL PLAYER CHOI ARRESTED
FOR MURDERING A PART-TIMER'S FATHER
PARTIALLY ADMITTED GUILT
AND SAID "IT WAS IMPULSIVE"
I was going to go home
after In-gang left.
But I went to her place instead.
He had asked me
and I remembered she hasn't been
sleeping well at night lately.
I wanted to keep her company.
I thought of you
as a gift from my daughter.
I scolded In-gang for doubting you
and pushing you away.
I reprimanded him for that.
You looked so pitiful
when I first saw you
so I believed
you could never do such a thing.
The one who deceived me...
No.
The one who deceived my whole family!
I foolishly trusted you
and I drove my own grandson...
into a bottomless pit.
What...
What should I do?
What am I supposed to do now, Ah-jin?
Can you explain what happened
before and after the fall?
A cat.
She went out to show me
the kitten that had come by.
A cat?
She used to feed
the stray cats in the neighborhood.
In-mo is allergic,
so she couldn't let them inside.
She had only put food out for them.
Sometimes, the cats would bring
their kittens
and show up at her door
at night.
Please continue.
After putting food out for them...
she was standing up...
when she suddenly swayed
as if she got dizzy.
Then, she lost consciousness.
I see.
I know this is hard
but I have a few more questions.
I'll take care of it.
I'll wipe every security camera
and dash cam clean
so get her away from here.
It's more natural
to say that I was here.
And there aren't
any security cameras here.
Don't do anything stupid.
A grandma fell down the stairs.
Please hurry.
Wait!
I'd like to know
exactly what kind of relationship
you have with Baek Ah-jin.
I looked you up.
The Nojeong-dong Rooftop Murder Case.
What does that have to do
with Dharma Sister Yeonhwa's passing?
I read that you testified
you were caught in a trap
set by the victim's daughter,
who worked part-time at your café.
What exactly are you trying to ask?
Is it whether there's a link
between Baek Ah-jin
and her father's murder?
Can you answer that?
You want an answer?
Between the murder
of Mr. Baek Seon-gyu...
and Ms. Baek Ah-jin...
there is no connection.
Sorry?
No connection whatsoever.
Back then, I testified like that
out of a cowardly wish
to slip through the law
because I was afraid
of becoming a criminal.
Which I regret now.
I served five years
and paid for my crime behind bars
but my debt to the deceased
is something I must carry for life.
Baek Ah-jin is
simply a bereaved daughter
who lost her family.
She's someone
I must keep apologizing to
until the day I die.
Since she became so famous
there will inevitably be
all kinds of rumors.
But they're baseless.
I'm relieved to hear that.
Thank you for coming.
Why did you tell him that?
It was a chance to get revenge.
Why defend me?
During my first year in prison...
I wondered what I'd do to you
once I got out...
and how to pay you back.
During the second year
I kept thinking...
"Why me, of all people?"
After the third winter...
I started thinking
about what could have driven you...
to do something so horrific.
And the year after that...
I began taking pity on you.
If you had had
even one proper adult in your life
as a child
I thought your path
might have been different.
So, in the last year
I decided to pray for you.
And I started wondering
if I could become
that one adult for you.
Once I thought about it that way
I stopped resenting you.
So, don't carry any guilt.
What happened then
was simply my fate.
That sounds just like you.
I'm going to root for you.
That's my way.
So, live your life
remembering there's someone out there
who genuinely pities you
and sincerely cheers for you.
Try living like that.
That's the best revenge I can offer.
But Mr. Choi.
There's no such thing
as "best revenge."
What just happened was
that you missed
your one and only chance
to take revenge on me.
Thank you.
HEO IN-GANG WAS KNOWN
TO BE DEEPLY AFFECTIONATE
TOWARD HIS GRANDMOTHER...
Baek Ah-jin and Heo In-gang?
How long are you going to milk them?
It works for the public.
They're like a bone broth.
You boil and boil,
and it still gives.
It's about time
they broke up, though.
I was going to lock in the breakup
as an exclusive
and be done with it.
Why split up a couple
that's doing fine?
Isn't it obvious?
Ah-jin is a rising sun,
and In-gang is a setting sun.
She's gotten everything
she could out of him.
Why would she keep dating him?
Who knows?
It could be true love.
"True love"? You don't know anything.
What do you want?
Oh, nothing.
I'm just calling to see
if there's anything new.
Nothing pulls clicks
like you and In-gang.
We're in mourning. Show some respect.
I have something to verify--
Hello?
Hello...
Right.
For a time like this...
RÉSUMÉ
PHOTO
Hello, Ms. Sim Sung-hee?
I told you I never did that.
It looks like Ah-jin's side
has already made a move.
Was it Longstar's CEO, Seo Mi-ri?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
If you're going to keep talking
nonsense, I'm hanging up.
I did what you told me to.
Guess you're scared, after all.
Figures.
Your dad's past
as an adulterous lawyer
and your own past,
stealing your classmates' stuff
beaten by the homeroom teacher
and kids
and forced to transfer.
It'll look bad on you
if those spread in your workplace.
You saw the comments
on your post last time, right?
Plenty of people still remember you.
So, unless you want
your past dragged out in the open
shut your mouth and lie low.
If not
I'll follow you around
with your past everywhere you go.
Fuck.
SAMYUN SEOUL HOSPITAL MEMORIAL HALL
Director.
Hello.
Are you heading out now?
Oh, Ms. Baek Ah-jin.
I'm glad you know my name.
I was nervous you might not.
Of course, I do.
I enjoyed your works.
Thank you.
I've watched all of yours as well.
I'm a big fan.
And In-gang talks about you so much.
He does?
I should buy him a meal sometime.
No need.
Since you came today
once he settles down,
let me treat you to a meal with him.
What do you say?
I'd love that. Anytime.
For today, please stay by him
and comfort him.
I will.
- Get home safe.
- Thanks.
Ms. Baek.
If you don't mind
how about you drop
by my studio sometime?
He must have seen Ah-jin
at In-gang's grandma's funeral.
He said she was the image
he'd been looking for
and wants her to play
a key role in his new work.
Director Seol Yeong-uk is...
It'll be invited
to the Cannes Film Festival
and that naturally opens
a route into the global market.
There's no better opportunity
for an actor.
It's what every actor dreams of.
In-gang's grandma left Ah-jin
a big gift as she passed.
You're curious, aren't you?
Whether I was the one
who did it to her that night.
What do you think?
Do you think I could go that far?
I don't get you.
It must have been hard
thinking about what to do with a girl
who even committed a murder.
Say it.
It wasn't you, right?
And what happens if it were me?
You're right.
She started getting on my nerves.
She was no use to me anymore
and constantly got in my way.
She had also found out
that I approached her on purpose.
So, what do you think I did to her?
Is that true?
Did you really do it?
Whatever you're thinking
is the truth.
Baek Ah-jin.
This is so exhausting.
Excuse me.
You're the grandson of the lady
who lived in Unit 401, right?
My grandma was crying?
Yes, she was practically wailing,
so I was shocked.
She normally doesn't do that.
By the time she calmed down
a pretty, young woman
walked into her place.
I brought her some red bean porridge
and saw something strange
at the door.
What was it?
Your grandma was pounding
the young woman's chest
saying things like, "I trusted you
who deceived my whole family."
It was something like that.
Also, the woman in Unit 409 said
someone kept stealing her packages
so she secretly set up
a camera in the hallway.
But it's illegal
so she probably didn't tell
the police.
But if your grandma fell
down the stairs
between the fourth and third floors
it might have been filmed.
Could I speak with her?
My husband saved
a copy of the footage just in case
but a detective came and got it.
I see.
Thank you.
Don't ever make me do
stuff like this again.
You, of all people,
should believe in Ah-jin, damn it.
- Did you see it?
- No.
I don't need to.
I believe her. She's innocent.
And don't worry about Sung-hee.
I gave her a good scare, so she won't
dare open her mouth again.
She won't be spreading stories
about Ah-jin.
Good.
In-gang, are you still in bed?
Yes, why?
Come on. You too?
I heard you backed out of the film
you were supposed to do.
We've got to hang in there
now more than ever.
Don't keep starving yourself.
Remember to eat.
Ah-jin brought me some porridge.
I'll have it later.
I saw you were asleep, so I left.
Don't skip meals, okay?
I love you.
HEO IN-GANG SPOTTED
SHOPPING FOR RINGS IN HONG KONG
There are headlines saying
you're about to get married now.
This is a problem, Ms. Baek.
You do know
what kind of character
you're playing, right?
If audiences can't stay
immersed in my film
because of your real-life romance
or marriage rumors
I've got no reason to cast you, do I?
I'm sorry.
I wasn't expecting
this kind of speculation, either.
I actually like
seeing you and In-gang together.
I got to work with you thanks to him,
and I appreciate that.
But let's keep personal
and professional matters separate.
You're not dumb enough
to confuse them
right?
No, Director.
Director, you're already here!
I came as early as I could.
Long time no see, Ms. Seo.
Hi.
I don't see Mr. Yoon, though.
Is he running late?
He said
we should meet on a better day.
He said today wasn't
the night for drinking.
Anyway, I'll get going.
Let's talk again soon.
Of course.
We'll see you soon.
Take care!
It must have been tough
cleaning up the mess.
I only posted a statement asking
to refrain from wild speculations.
What about In-gang?
When has he ever cared
about articles?
His fans are already freaking out
that he can't get married yet.
But he's talking about retiring
once his contract's over.
It's driving me insane.
He really said that?
He didn't tell you?
I had my phone turned off.
It was getting too chaotic
due to all the calls coming in.
You didn't know
about the ring, either, did you?
No.
Are you going to marry him?
No, I'm going to end it.
You'll back me up, right?
Ah-jin.
While preparing for your birthday
I realized
it was the first time in my life
I had ever felt so deeply grateful
that someone was born.
I suddenly understood how huge
my feelings for you had become.
This must be love.
Let's share our lives together.
Let's fill and exchange our love
within the same everyday life.
I want to marry you.
You're home, right?
I'll be at your place in ten minutes.
We need to talk.
Will you stay by my side?
What are you hesitating about?
Is it something exciting?
Something scary.
I'm not sure if I can handle it.
Scary?
Like what?
It's just scary.
Then throw it away.
I wish I could.
Why isn't he home yet?
Man.
What are you doing?
Wait, who are you?
"Who are you?"
Are you serious?
Don't you even remember the guy
you hugged last time?
Go make some ramyeon.
I'm sorry?
It's for Jun-seo's stomach.
He needs something spicy to sober up.
Jackass.
Gosh.
I was worried
something had happened to you.
It relieves me to see your face.
In-gang,
are you thinking of retiring?
Did Mi-ri tell you?
Why didn't you tell me first?
I didn't mean to hide it.
It wasn't easy to make up my mind.
I was going to tell you
once I was sure.
Are you planning to marry me
after you retire?
I thought we were on the same page.
Was I wrong?
Then you shouldn't have let it
become news.
What?
I feel awful.
Do you have any idea
how humiliated I was
in front of the director today?
Why should I have to take
that kind of criticism
because of you?
Ah-jin.
Let me ask you one favor.
You're a good guy who always
does me a favor when I ask
so I hope you do it again this time.
Let's break up.
Hang on.
What kind of nonsense is this?
This is too sudden.
I know you're angry, but...
Are you even the same Ah-jin I know?
And are you the In-gang I know?
You're not in your right mind.
You can't even control your emotions
babbling about retiring
and fairy-tale dreams.
Get a grip.
Do you know how many fans you've lost
in the year we've been together?
And now you want me to marry you?
Don't make me laugh.
And what about me?
You want to put
a "married woman" label on me
while I lose my movie roles,
so I can watch as my career dies?
How can a person change
so completely overnight?
Why?
You don't like the new me?
Then would you rather have me
smile sweetly
while I break up with you?
Would that make it easier for you?
We've been together a year.
I thought I knew you,
and I was certain about us.
That's why I pictured
a future together.
Was that so wrong?
You know how much pain
I'm in right now.
Can't you even try to understand--
Why should I understand you?
It wasn't ten years,
not even five years.
Who cares
about a one-year relationship?
You thought I knew you? Well, I...
I've never heard
such an arrogant thing in my life.
I can't believe this.
I wish this were a dream.
Given your tragic life
I'm probably not
even nightmare-worthy.
Don't make a scene over something
as ordinary as a breakup.
Ah-jin, what's wrong?
Come on.
- Don't do this.
- In-gang.
What I'm about to say
will hurt.
I'm already hurting.
You were pretending ignorance.
But listen anyway.
Don't try to avoid it.
Your grandma's notebook.
I stole it.
I wanted to win her favor
so I could date you.
She found it at my place a while ago
and she found out...
what kind of person I am.
And from that shock
she...
You understand what I mean, right?
In-gang.
How you fell
in love with me...
and what happened to your grandma--
What the hell did you do?
All I did was...
tell her the truth.
I asked what you did to my grandma!
I simply told her honestly.
For once in my life.
Say that again.
If you don't let go of me now
you'll be in hell
every time you think of her.
You're not the type of person
who can handle that.
So, admit it.
Our ending was already decided.
I'll release the breakup article
through a reporter I know
at the right time.
The reason will be
"grew apart due to busy schedules."
About Ms. Seo...
I'll tell her myself,
so get some rest for now.
You look like you haven't slept
since your grandma passed.
Get a good sleep.
It's me, Mr. Lim.
What is it, at this hour?
I think it's time to end
our little arrangement.
What?
Don't tell me
you're going to marry In-gang.
No, it's the opposite.
The opposite?
Get a breakup article ready for us.
Breakup? Hold on.
Just write we drifted apart
due to our busy schedules.
- You're seriously going through--
- As quickly as possible, please.
CEO SEO MI-RI
Hey, Boss.
Where are you?
Boss, don't pull over.
Just keep driving.
You've got a tail behind you.
Who are you?
Are you a stalker?
Or gangsters?
You've got nothing better
to do with your lives?
Get out.
Get him.
- No!
- Punk.
Let's stop all this.
Forget about Ah-jin now.
She's not the right girl for you.
We won't renew her contract, either.
I know.
All lovers break up in the end.
This kind of breakup happens
to everybody.
Just today.
I'll let it hurt just for today.
Just for today?
Fine. Let's drink, then.
Let's get totally wasted tonight.
It brings back old memories.
Thanks, Mi-ri.
For what?
Thank you.
Silly.
Pour me some more. Is this a joke?
AH-JIN
Hey, Ah-jin.
Jae-oh, who was in that car
that was following me?
Paparazzi.
I talked to them and sent them away
so don't worry.
You didn't call me out
for something urgent, right?
No, I'm a little tired today.
I'll talk to you later.
I'll call you.
What?
HEO IN-GANG AND BAEK AH-JIN
BREAK UP AFTER 1 YEAR
GREW DISTANT DUE TO BUSY SCHEDULES
THE FAMOUS COUPLE
HEO IN-GANG AND BAEK AH-JIN
ENDED THEIR RELATIONSHIP
AFTER A TURBULENT YEAR
Ms. Seo, these documents are for you.
Yes, fix the parts I marked.
Where's In-gang?
His manager called and said
he just went to bed
after taking sleeping pills.
He won't be up
until late afternoon, then.
That brat probably skipped food
and poured alcohol
into an empty stomach.
Is there
a good hangover-soup place nearby?
Are you taking it to him?
I'll swing by his place
on my way home.
I need to make him eat something
and pull himself together.
I'm out of town right now
but In-gang isn't picking up
the phone.
He's just passed out
from drinking too much.
I'm heading over
with hangover soup now.
I'll feed him
and tell him to call you.
Yes.
Don't worry, In-mo.
Focus on your work.
Okay.
In-gang, wake up!
Time to fix that hangover.
I brought you
some amazing hangover soup.
He's still asleep, huh?
In-gang!
Where is he?
In-gang.
In-gang, no.
No!
Hey.
Look at me.
Ridiculous, right?
What happened?
You've never been this hurt.
What have you been doing?
I just got unlucky.
How's Boss?
What?
Is she all right?
Why are you asking that?
As long as nothing happened to her.
Who the hell were those guys, anyway?
Heo In-gang is dead.
Seriously? Was it suicide?
But he recently broke up
with Baek Ah-jin.
Wait, does that mean
he killed himself because of her?
That can't be.
Apparently, he had depression.
What did you say to me before?
What did you say to me last time?
You said you were just going to have
a normal relationship and break up.
You said yourself
that he wouldn't get hurt.
You're hilarious.
Why are you angry?
Who are you to yell at me?
He couldn't accept the breakup.
That's on him.
I did everything I could.
How is that my fault?
It was bad luck on his part
that he ended up like that.
That's not my fault.
He's dead.
An entire family was shattered
in an instant.
And that's all you have to say?
You make it sound like I killed him.
Didn't you?
Did you think I'd feel guilty?
Don't expect that from me.
You're the only one
who'll end up hurt and disappointed.
Can't you just...
live like a normal person?
It was my mistake
for thinking you had
even a shred of humanity in you.
How exactly
am I supposed to be human?
Do you think things would have
turned out differently
if you had pulled me
out of that bathtub?
But you didn't.
Jae-oh would have stormed
into the bathroom
and smashed that woman's head,
but you didn't.
And you dare to judge me?
Did you just stand there and watch
because you had humanity?
This isn't my fault.
You made me like this.
If you feel bad for me,
say you're sorry.
Say you're sorry
you turned me into this.
When you condemn me
you're actually condemning
your past self.
You can blame me all you want
but I'll never blame you.
If you want to leave me, then do it.
Run away from me
just like you did in the past...
and I still won't blame you.
Because you're the first person
I chose to keep by my side.
I was afraid my grandma
wouldn't be able to get her surgery.
Thank you, Manager.
I'll never forget this.
I'm not a manager anymore.
You can call me CEO now.
And just so you know
I never forget
a favor I gave, either.
Thank you, truly.
Hello.
You said you never forget
a favor you've done.
I wish you massive success, Ms. Seo.
Thank you.
REPRESENTATIVE: SEO MI-RI
NAME: HEO IN-GANG
I never forget
the favors I receive, either.
I sure know
how to pick the right people.
I just want to thank you.
HEO IN-GANG
Everyone ends up abandoned
and broken in life.
You were just too weak.
I couldn't just fall apart with you.
Please understand me.
- Kick her out!
Kick Baek Ah-jin out!
This is unfair!
- Unfair!
Take responsibility, Longstar!
- Take responsibility!
This is unfair!
- Unfair!
Baek Ah-jin is a criminal!
- Criminal!
Kick Baek Ah-jin out!
- Kick her out!
Bring In-gang back!
- Bring him back!
Take responsibility, Longstar!
- Take responsibility!
Bring In-gang back!
- Bring him back!
Baek Ah-jin!
- Bring him back.
- Bring In-gang back.
- Devil!
- You're the worst!
Who are you? Move!
I was her classmate.
She doesn't deserve all this insult!
- Where do you think you're going?
- Go away!
- Come back here!
- Baek Ah-jin!
- You're a devil!
- Bring him back to life!
- Stop!
- Bring In-gang back!
- Get away from her!
- Come here!
Who the heck is she?
Hey, I'm all filthy because of you,
so let me wash up first.
Seriously.
Hey.
You have a nice place.
So fancy.
This is insane.
You have lots of nice clothes.
I missed you.
Not bad for an orphan.
You're successful now.
Impressive, friend.
Bring me some booze.
You drink, right?
Right?
Get out of my house.
You used to run loan-shark schemes
on kids back in school
and now look at you.
Let me try that scheme, too.
How about 100,000 won a day?
Don't pick fights you can't win,
and get out.
Fine.
For now...
I'll take this and call it even.
The public sentiment
is extremely negative.
Longstar also hasn't made
a clear statement yet
so speculative articles
are flooding in.
The agency's actor is under attack,
and they're merely watching?
I know you were digging
into Ah-jin's father's death
and stopped
when you started working with her.
I suggest you work with me now.
We may not be able
to reopen the whole case
but this will be enough
to drag her down
since she lives off public image.
Is this everything?
Just a portion.
I'll give you the rest
as soon as you agree.
Think about it and get back to me.
Ms. Seo.
You do know timing is everything
with exposés, right?
About that timing...
The sooner, the better.
What are you doing?
I'm sorry.
Ah-jin.
Is this a new persona
you're trying out?
Sorry about what, exactly?
I truly want to apologize.
For everything I've done...
I'm sorry.
Ah-jin.
After all this time?
I'm even on my knees.
Won't you please accept my apology?
Please?
Why should I?
Why should I accept your apology?
Ms. Hwang.
For kneeling once?
Considering everything
you've done to me
your knees should be
worn down to the bones.
Deep down, you've been waiting
for my apology.
I don't need it.
Is that right?
Well, I apologized.
Don't forget to tell Jun-seo
that I came and apologized.
Make sure he knows
I got on my knees.
Do you know...
when I hated you the most?
I asked what you did to my grandma!
I admit
that was my intention at first.
But...
I liked
In-gang so much.
So, I...
wanted you to love me, too.
I'll take care of it.
I'll tell
In-gang the truth...
and end this.
Look at me.
I still stand by it.
The fact
that you're also one of my children
just like In-gang and In-mo.
When your child does wrong,
you scold them
and embrace them again.
That's what a parent does.
Ah-jin.
Baek Ah-jin.
Yes?
You did wrong, didn't you?
You won't do it again, right?
That's good enough.
Ah-jin.
Here's what we should do.
We'll keep this just between us
and never tell anyone.
My other babies must have arrived.
Do you want to meet them?
I hated you the most
when you were kind to me
every once in a while.
Because I would be tricked
by your kindness
and start to fall for it.
I was afraid of having
even a tiny bit of false hope.
That's what scared me.
Come on. Come.
But now I know for sure.
It's all my fault.
Save her life.
Please save her life.
In hell, hope is...
something you should never hold onto.
They don't seem to know
who we are yet.
It looks like he followed us
by coincidence.
She's hospitalized at the moment.
What would you have me do?
Let's observe for now.
Find out exactly
how they're connected.
Yes, sir.
DEAR X
Subtitles by Ho-young Yun